<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Paul Coghlan's Public Scratchpad</title><link>https://paulcoghlan.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Paul Coghlan's Public Scratchpad</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><copyright>Paul Coghlan</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 18:29:26 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://paulcoghlan.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Tips for using AWS Lambda Runtime Interface Emulator</title><link>https://paulcoghlan.github.io/posts/using-aws-lambda-rie/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 18:29:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://paulcoghlan.github.io/posts/using-aws-lambda-rie/</guid><description>Scenario I&amp;rsquo;ve found the AWS Lambda Runtime Interface Emulator (RIE) to be a very useful tool to help develop custom Docker images for AWS Lambdas - but I&amp;rsquo;ve not seen it mentioned much in blogs or StackOverflow, etc.
My scenario was that I needed to develop a service to read a SQS message containing a HTML link, convert the HTML to PDF, and upload the PDF to S3.
I was using wkhtmltopdf HTML to PDF convertor (basically a headless Chrome Browser), with some SQS/S3 integration glue code in Kotlin to align with the rest of the codebase.</description></item><item><title>Ikea Homestudio Lights</title><link>https://paulcoghlan.github.io/posts/ikea-homestudio-lights/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 16:34:28 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://paulcoghlan.github.io/posts/ikea-homestudio-lights/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve built an automated home studio lighting setup for less than $100 which I believe produces more flattering images whilst being unobtrusive enough to look part of a typical desk environment.
My setup is based on two $39/£29 IKEA Skurup desk lamps.
I bought some Osram Zigbee E14 LED lights from Amazon UK when they were discounted to £4.49, and with the help of a vice I very carefully popped the plastic cover off:</description></item><item><title>Diy Teleprompter</title><link>https://paulcoghlan.github.io/posts/diy-teleprompter/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 15:34:58 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://paulcoghlan.github.io/posts/diy-teleprompter/</guid><description>Being able to look someone in the eye is something we take for granted when we meet someone face-to-face, but this is tricky with desktop monitors.
I wanted a compact, inexpensive teleprompter to fit between my two desktop monitors to show me my Zoom window and look directly at my webcam.
The problem with the less expensive teleprompter models is that they tend to be made of plastic, and so unable to support anything heavier than a tablet/phone.</description></item><item><title>My First Post</title><link>https://paulcoghlan.github.io/posts/my-first-post/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 12:32:35 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://paulcoghlan.github.io/posts/my-first-post/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>